<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
 <title>Denis Tsoi</title>
 <link href="http://username.github.io/" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://username.github.io"/>
 <updated>2013-10-15T23:48:29+08:00</updated>
 <id>http://username.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Denis Tsoi</name>
   <email>blah@email.test</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>The Birth of Denistsoi.github.io</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.io/2013/10/12/first-post"/>
   <updated>2013-10-12T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.io/2013/10/12/first-post</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been quite a hectic couple of months for me and today is probably the first time that I&amp;#8217;ve felt alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that it sounds like a bad thing, but there hasn&amp;#8217;t been much of an opportunity for me to just sit down and reflect on what has been happening in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was a Precious Metals Dealer for Acetop Precious Metals based in Hong Kong.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I took a General Assembly Front End Web Development class in May 2013.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I left my Dealer job to become a Developer in August 2013.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I joined Imagination Hong Kong a week after I left my previous job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m the type of person who likes to keep busy&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember a story about where James Brown got his work ethic. It was a story about how hard his father had to work, doing all kinds of jobs&amp;#8230; and he was only out of work 7 days throughout his entire life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about that&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be thinking&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;But&amp;#8230; I&amp;#8217;m not the father of the Godfather of Soul&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes - you might not be&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but YOU could BE the influence for someone to make a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; &amp;#8230; &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remembered during my times at University as a pinnicle phase of my life&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230;where I had become disappointed at my life choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t REALLY know what I was doing and didn&amp;#8217;t have the confidence to admit to myself that I was feeling lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I went into University, I had the feeling that I could do a degree in the fastest pace possible and that I even entertained with the idea of doing a sandwich degree (doing full year work experience inbetween my degree).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had listened to professors (whenever I went to the prospective interviews) that doing work experience inbetween would not be the wisest of decisions&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I accepted that advice as if those very professors knew WHO I was&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but&amp;#8230; Why did I?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, I believed that people older than I was, whether they were teachers or my older peers knew best&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but&amp;#8230; How did I come to that conclusion?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never realised at the time that I was responsible to make the final decision&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had failed my year, and had to spend a summer in order to retake my year. During that summer, I had felt depressed and lost and needed motivation to get through the summer on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was around this time that I discovered Tony Robbins and Robin Sharma. The inspirational people that I gravitated towards was Ghandi and Einstein.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;...&amp;quot;Be the change you want to see&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to enjoy life? - to Really be content on life itself?&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Birth of Denistsoi.github.io</title>
   <link href="http://username.github.io/2013/09/21/the-birth-of-denistsoigithubio"/>
   <updated>2013-09-21T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://username.github.io/2013/09/21/the-birth-of-denistsoigithubio</id>
   <content type="html"></content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>