<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>Denis Tsoi</title>
        <description>Denis Tsoi - Denis Tsoi</description>
        <link>http://username.github.io</link>
        <link>http://username.github.io</link>
        <lastBuildDate>2013-11-11T14:30:42+08:00</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>2013-11-11T14:30:42+08:00</pubDate>
        <ttl>1800</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>First Post!</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been quite a hectic couple of months for me and today is probably the first time that I&amp;#8217;ve felt alone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that it sounds like a bad thing, but there hasn&amp;#8217;t been much of an opportunity for me to just sit down and reflect on what has been happening in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I was a Precious Metals Dealer for Acetop Precious Metals based in Hong Kong.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I took a General Assembly Front End Web Development class in May 2013.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I left my Dealer job to become a Developer in August 2013.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;I joined Imagination Hong Kong a week after I left my previous job.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m the type of person who likes to keep busy&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really busy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember a story about where James Brown got his work ethic. It was a story about how hard his father had to work, doing all kinds of jobs&amp;#8230; and he was only out of work 7 days throughout his entire life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about that&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;7 days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might be thinking&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8220;But&amp;#8230; I&amp;#8217;m not the father of the Godfather of Soul&amp;#8221;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes - you might not be&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but YOU could BE the influence for someone to make a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230; &amp;#8230; &amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remembered during my times at University as a pinnicle phase of my life&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230;where I had become disappointed at my life choices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn&amp;#8217;t REALLY know what I was doing and didn&amp;#8217;t have the confidence to admit to myself that I was feeling lost.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I went into University, I had the feeling that I could do a degree in the fastest pace possible and that I even entertained with the idea of doing a sandwich degree (doing full year work experience inbetween my degree).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had listened to professors (whenever I went to the prospective interviews) that doing work experience inbetween would not be the wisest of decisions&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I accepted that advice as if those very professors knew WHO I was&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but&amp;#8230; Why did I?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the time, I believed that people older than I was, whether they were teachers or my older peers knew best&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but&amp;#8230; How did I come to that conclusion?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I never realised at the time that I was responsible to make the final decision&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had failed my year, and had to spend a summer in order to retake my year. During that summer, I had felt depressed and lost and needed motivation to get through the summer on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was around this time that I discovered Tony Robbins and Robin Sharma. The inspirational people that I gravitated towards was Ghandi and Einstein.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;...&amp;quot;Be the change you want to see&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What does it mean to enjoy life? - to Really be content on life itself?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/2013/10/12/first-post</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/2013/10/12/first-post</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-10-12T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Going for Gold</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Going for Gold&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I handed my resignation letter. I&amp;#8217;ve been spouting about doing it for ages now, probably for months. (and for the facebook community, you must be sick to death by it so I apologize in advance). I guess the thing that always frightened me was always the fear of uncertainty&amp;#8230; the fear of having nothing to do and no money coming in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, this past year has been incredible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve experienced so many obstacles and personal disappointments&amp;#8230; but they&amp;#8217;ve all lead me to appreciate the incredible relationships that I&amp;#8217;ve made; all within the Hong Kong community. From appreciating Eric, my older brother, confidant and most trusted advisor&amp;#8230; to the many inspiring people that have shown nothing but support by sharing their stories of trials and tribulations. I&amp;#8217;m not entirely sure how I feel&amp;#8230; but the closest thing would be a mix of uncertainty and fear to relief, determination and elation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last night at Hackjam, I experienced a very moving conversation with Tom Grek and how he realized that all the fear from leaving a safe job were completely unfounded. That with talent and skill, work will always come your way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That really stuck with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I mean&amp;#8230;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It made me realize, that with all the projects; from PrinterLinker and receiving support from the Makible team, being a Community Organizer for Dim Sum Labs, a GA Evangelist and Hacker For hire; that they all give me PLENTY of things to do&amp;#8230; and somehow&amp;#8230; it makes perfect sense just to &amp;#8220;go for gold&amp;#8221;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though I have to mention something which is a slight tangent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t do well in crowds and whenever I&amp;#8217;m in a situation where I&amp;#8217;m in front of a group of people, I have to sum up ALL my courage and energy to try and make every word have an emotive impact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For someone that doesn&amp;#8217;t like to talk or appear showy&amp;#8230; it helps to assume an identity&amp;#8230; THAT being the identity of a &amp;#8220;Community Organizer&amp;#8221; for DSL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I guess the &amp;#8220;Community Organizer&amp;#8221; is the guy who always gives a little more than they&amp;#8217;re normally used to. The person who offers a helping hand when someone needs it. The person who holds their tongue to avoid offending someone and having a partition of patience when they&amp;#8217;re extremely tired. The person who says &amp;#8220;hi&amp;#8221; not because they&amp;#8217;re trained to do it, but because something inside them tells them that they HAVE to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve seen people I admire do the above (and also have the pleasure of calling my friends). The past few months, I&amp;#8217;ve seen notable three people do this to extremes: Mart Van de Ven, Allison Baum, Graham Leach (&amp;amp; DSL).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve seen Mart do this, almost to a fault, on numerous occasions and I&amp;#8217;m always impressed every time he does this. Like, it&amp;#8217;s impeccable. I mean, having a job is tough enough in HK, but to do that AND to teach at twice a week with newbies like myself? - &amp;#8230; I wonder, &amp;#8220;does the passion for learning burn so brightly that it gives people energy to extinguish negativity and doubt?&amp;#8221;&amp;#8230; It must do. I remember talking to Mart after our last FEWD class and mentioning how if I had someone with Mart&amp;#8217;s energy and positivity during my Secondary education, I would have became a Computer Scientist rather than delving into finance. It&amp;#8217;s with him agreeing to BEING that person for people now that really inspires me to do more, not just for myself, but for people like myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With Allison calling herself a self-professed introvert, it amazes me how she can drive that energy and kindness when talking to people. It&amp;#8217;s hard work, for any startup, to say or even prove that your product is far superior to anything out there. It&amp;#8217;s even harder trying to convince people that the curriculum and community that GA provides has more advantages that going Solo. Whenever I go some of these GA info sessions, I sometimes get a feeling of reluctance from people&amp;#8230; I mean &amp;#8220;Why&amp;#8221; would anyone in their right mind purchase a product to learn?&amp;#8230; then I&amp;#8217;d answer with&amp;#8230; &amp;#8220;Why&amp;#8221; are people getting better paid jobs with perks in the Tech Community?&amp;#8230; Think about it this way, The current renaissance that exists is IN TECH. NOT in Finance. If you want to be EXCELLENT - then TECH is the EASIEST way to do just THAT. I&amp;#8217;m not saying you have to quit your job and start a business to make your first million. Frankly, I couldn&amp;#8217;t care less if I do or not&amp;#8230; What I AM saying is&amp;#8230; when I&amp;#8217;m long into my career, what kind of skills would I want to have I picked up that will STILL be applicable? - I will be damned if I get replaced by a factory of robotic coders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, with Graham Leach. He comes across as someone pretty intense and radical. Not being satisfied with the status quo - he&amp;#8217;s inspired me to be &amp;#8220;Tenacious against Complacency&amp;#8221;. Honestly&amp;#8230; It&amp;#8217;s intimidating being apart of a Hackerspace/Makerspace. People around you are Incredibly smart, more experienced at things that you&amp;#8217;ve never heard about. However, they are an incredible group of people that provide the utmost support whenever they see you struggling. They&amp;#8217;ve all gone through it&amp;#8230; and often, having the courage to just ask after experiencing some struggle will help IMMENSELY.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;#8217;t know a lot of people in the startup community personally. I mean, I wish I had the time to get to know people. It takes me a couple of weeks to get to hear people&amp;#8217;s stories. &amp;#8220;Why did they choose to be in Hong Kong?&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;What are their interests?&amp;#8221;, &amp;#8220;what problems are they trying to solve now?&amp;#8221; - I mean, stack those three questions and multiply that with the numerous people in the community&amp;#8230; That&amp;#8217;s A LOT of man hours! It isn&amp;#8217;t that I don&amp;#8217;t want to know WHO you are&amp;#8230; it&amp;#8217;s just that I can&amp;#8217;t physically do it all and STILL go for GOLD. Even though we&amp;#8217;re all in the same boat one way or another, it&amp;#8217;s deeply moving that people say a short hello or a few words of encouragement. I mean, everyone I&amp;#8217;ve mentioned today, they&amp;#8217;ve all gone through the troughs in the valley of despair&amp;#8230; but we&amp;#8217;re all in the same journey for different reasons. I think that this positivity should occur more often in the community. Don&amp;#8217;t come into the scene thinking you&amp;#8217;re gonna be the next Facebook&amp;#8230; do it because you can and it&amp;#8217;s the right thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So in summary&amp;#8230; If you&amp;#8217;re feeling good about yourself&amp;#8230; share the gold&amp;#8230; give some positive encouragement to someone who needs it&amp;#8230; shake the hand of someone you haven&amp;#8217;t met before&amp;#8230; you never know&amp;#8230; you might need a little encouragement when you need it most.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To the people who inspire me, to those who have said a few friendly words and to those who continue to give me support&amp;#8230; Thank You. D&lt;/p&gt;</description>
                <link>http://username.github.io/2013/07/02/Going-for-Gold</link>
                <guid>http://username.github.io/2013/07/02/Going-for-Gold</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-07-02T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>
